Guide to the John Melmoth Dow papers, 1798-1918.
Dow, John Melmoth papers, 1798-1918.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
John Melmoth Dow papers, 1798-1918.
2765
John Melmoth, Dow 1827-1892.
6.4 cubic ft.
Financial Records, Legal Documents, Correspondence, Printed Materials.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Personal and professional papers of John M. Dow. Also included are letters and newspaper clippings concerning political events in Central America in the second half of the nineteenth century. Dow also pursued his interests as a naturalist, exploring the Central American coast to collect marine flora and fauna.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
John Melmoth Dow was a shipmaster, shipping agent and naturalist. Born in New York City in 1827, he joined the Panama Railroad Company. He made his first voyage to the Central American coast in 1851, and remained involved with Central and South American coastal trade as a ship captain until 1876. He was appointed commander of the steamer Constitution in 1853, and opened the Central American service of the Panama Railroad Company as commander of the steamer Colombus. He later became a shipping agent for the Pacific Mail Steamship Company. During his years as a shipping agent, Dow was captured and held hostage by revolutionist Pedro Prest án in 1885. He was arbitrator in the dispute between the Compagnie Universelle du Canal Interocéanique and the American Contracting and Dredging Company in their attempt to build the French Canal in Panama. Dow died in New York City in 1892.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Personal and professional papers of John M. Dow include shipping and trading contracts with Central American governments; administrative records, cargo and freight (primarily coffee and indigo) statements; and financial and commercial records, annual reports, logs, schedules, and telegraph code. Also included are letters and newspaper clippings concerning political events in Central America in the second half of the nineteenth century; correspondence with Central American politicians such as General Barrios, Rafael Zaldívar and Enrico Palacio regarding United States policy toward attempts to unify the Central American countries into a single federation. Also included is Dow's correspondence as arbitrator in the settlement between the Compagnie Universelle du Canal Interocéanique and the American Contracting and Dredging Company, 1887. Dow also pursued his interests as a naturalist, exploring the Central American coast to collect marine flora and fauna and carrying on an extensive correspondence with Professor Spencer Baird of the Smithsonian Institution and Osbert Salvin and P. L. Sclater of the Zoological Society of London concerning the collection and transportation of specimens native to Central America. Papers also contain several letters to his wife, Elizabeth Allen Dow, which provide daily accounts of his life on board ship and in port.
Among other correspondents are William Henry Aspinwall, John Cassin, Alexander Center, William Pancoast Clyde, Charles Dorat, John Charles Frémont, Joseph I. Henry, David Hoadley, J. B. Houston, J. Jacquier, Joseph F. Joy, W. H. Lane, George Newbold, James Orton, Henry Shelton Sanford, George Ure Skinner, Henry Bartholomew Slaven and Jeffries Wyman. Eight diaries kept by Dow provide comments on his daily life, and two notebooks give descriptions of the coast of Central America. Photographs include Dow and several Central American scenes. An album contains portraits of Dow's family, relatives and acquaintances, and well-known persons. There are two albums of caricatures and a book of "Ocean Mosses" (pressed specimens) given to Elizabeth Allen "from her friend Capt'n John M. Dow." Remaining items include a significant group of nineteenth century maps, membership certificates, inventories of property, bills, bank books, insurance policies, memoranda, passenger lists, menus, invitations, and printed matter pertaining primarily to natural history.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Dow, John Melmoth, 1827-1892.; Allen, Elizabeth.; Aspinwall, William Henry.; Baird, Spencer Fullerton, 1823-1887.; Barrios, Gerardo, General.; Cassin, John.; Center, Alexander.; Clyde, William Pancoast.; Goldblatt, Charles.; Dow, Elizabeth Allen.; Dow family.; Frémont, John Charles, 1813-1890.; Henry, Joseph I., 1797-1878.; Hoadley, David.; Houston, J. B.; Jacquier, J.; Joy, Joseph F.; Lane, W. H.; Newbold, George.; Orton, James.; Palacio, Enrico.; Prestán, Pedro.; Salvin, Osbert, 1835-1898.; Sclater, Philip Lutley, 1829-1913.; Sanford, H. S., 1823-1891.; Skinner, George Ure.; Slaven, Henry Bartholomew.; Wyman, Jeffries, 1864-; Zaldívar, Rafael, 1834-1903.; Allen, Elizabeth; Aspinwall, William Henry; Baird, Spencer Fullerton, 1823-1887; Barrios, Gerardo, General; Cassin, John; Center, Alexander; Clyde, William Pancoast; Dow, Elizabeth Allen; Dow family; Frémont, John Charles, 1813-1890; Goldblatt, Charles; Henry, Joseph I., 1797-1878; Hoadley, David; Houston, J. B.; Jacquier, J.; Joy, Joseph F.; Lane, W. H.; Newbold, George; Orton, James; Palacio, Enrico; Prestán, Pedro; Salvin, Osbert, 1835-1898; Sanford, H. S., 1823-1891; Sclater, Philip Lutley, 1829-1913; Skinner, George Ure; Slaven, Henry Bartholomew; Wyman, Jeffries, 1864-; Zalvídar, Rafael, 1834-1896; American Contract and Dredging Company.; Colombus (ship); Compagnie Universelle du Canal Interocéanique de Panama.; Constitution (ship); Pacific Mail Steamship Company.; Panama Railroad Co.; Smithsonian Institution.; Zoological Society of London.; Compagnie universelle du canal interocéanique de Panama; Constitution (Ship); Pacific Mail Steamship Company; Panama Railroad Co.; Smithsonian Institution; Zoological Society of London
Subjects:
Canals, Interoceanic.; Canals -- Design and construction.; Cargo handling.; Caricatures and cartoons.; Coastal plants.; Coastwise shipping.; Coffee industry.; Freight and freightage.; Indigo.; Marine plants.; Marine animals.; Mosses.; Natural history.; Ships -- Cargo.; Naturalists.; Shipmasters.; Canals -- Design and construction; Canals, Interoceanic; Cargo handling; Cargo ships; Caricatures and cartoons; Coastal plants; Coastwise shipping; Coffee industry; Commerce; Diplomatic relations; Freight and freightage; Indigo; Marine animals; Marine plants; Mosses; Natural history; Naturalists; Political science; Ship captains; Travel
Places:
Central America -- Commerce -- United States.; Central America -- Description and travel.; Central America -- Foreign relations.; Central America -- Politics and government.; Panama Canal (Panama); South America -- Commerce -- United States.; South America -- Description and travel.; South America -- Foreign relations.; South America -- Politics and government.; United States -- Commerce -- Central America.; United States -- Commerce -- South America.; Central America; Panama -- Panama Canal; South America; United States
Form and Genre Terms:
Contracts.; Diaries.; Logs (records).; Maps.; Menus.; Notebooks.; Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Correspondence and Related Papers
Series II. Letterbook
Series III. Logs, Diaries, and Nautical Guide
Series IV. Personal Papers
Series V. Photographs
Series VI. Miscellany and Memorabilia
Series VII. Publications
Series VIII. Mapcase Folders
CONTAINER LIST
- Correspondence and Related Papers, 1855-1893
  - Business and Natural History, 1855-1858 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Contains letters, resolutions, and orders
    Dorat, Charles
    Aspinwall, William Henry
    Dwight, Theodore
    Baird, Spencer Fullerton
    Smithsonian Institution
    Panama Railroad Company
    Pacific Mail Steamship Company
    San Salvador mines
    New York state
  - Business and Natural History, 1859-1860 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Contains letters, clippings, and a resolution
    Aspinwall, William H.
    Baird, Spencer F.
    Hoadley, David
    Sanford, Henry Shelton
    LeConte, John Lawrence
  - Business and Natural History Correspondence, 1861-01-1861-06 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Contains letters
    Joy, Joseph F.
    Barrios, Gerardo
    Bustamante, Borja
    San Jose, Guatemala
  - Business Correspondence, 1861-07-1861-09 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Lara Napoleon
    United States
  - Business Correspondence, 1861-10-1862-12 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Dow, John Melmoth
    Palacio, Enrico
    El Salvador
    Guatemala
  - Business and Natural History, 1863 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Contains letters, lists, and translations
    Salvin, Osbert
    Sociedad Economica de Amigos de Guatemala
  - Natural History, 1864 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Contains letters and a list
    Sociedad Economica
  - Natural History, 1865 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Contains letters and an illustration
    Wyman, Jeffries
    Stimpson, William
  - Natural History Correspondence, 1866 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Skinner, George Ure
    Sclater, Philip L.
    British Museum
    Zoological Society of London
  - Business and Natural History Correspondence, 1867-01-1867-08 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Business and Natural History, 1867-09-1868-12 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Henry, Joseph
    Torres, Father Cresencio
    Mexico
  - Natural History, 1869-01-1870-06 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Contains letters and a memorandum
    Lawrence, George Newbold
  - Natural History Correspondence, 1870-07-1871-07 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Endres, A. R.
  - Natural History Correspondence, 1871-08-1872-12 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Newcomb, Wesley
    Marsh, Othniel Charles
    Yale College
  - Business and Natural History Correspondence, 1873-1875 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Business and Natural History, 1876-1878 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Contains letters, legal documents, and a telegram
    Clyde, William Pancoast
  - Natural History, 1879-1881 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Contains letters and a resolution
  - Business and Natural History Correspondence, 1882-1883-06 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Lane, W. H.
    Dow, Allan Wade
  - Business and Natural History, 1883-08-1884-08 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Contains letters and a time statement
  - Business and Natural History, 1884-09-1884-12 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Contains letters, memorandums, and clippings
    Pim, Bedford
  - Business, 1885-01-1885-03 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Contains letters, lists, declarations, a book cover, a telegram, and translations
    Zaldivar, Rafael
    Baza, Francisco Mendiola
    Office of the Secretary General
    Colombia
    Salvador
    Panama
    Republic of Central America
  - Business, 1885-04-1885-09 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Contains letters and translated telegrams
    Dow, Elizabeth
  - Business, 1885-10-1885-12 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Contains letters, petitions, resolutions, and a statement
    Saville, James H.
    Saville and Starring
  - Business Correspondence, 1886 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Contains letters and a telegram
    Slaven, H. B.
    American Contracting and Dredging Company
    Compagnie Universelle du Canal Interoceanique
  - Business and Natural History, 1887-01-1887-04 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Contains letters and a translation
    Tacquier, T.
    Robinson, Tracy
    Panama Canal
  - Business, 1887-05-02-1887-05-18 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    Contains letters and questions
  - Business, 1887-05-21-1887-05-28 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    Contains letters, translations, questions, and opinions
  - Business - arbitration, 1887-06-1887-08 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    Contains letters, translations, questions, statements, and canal profiles
  - Business, 1887-09-1888-01 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Contains letters and job applications
  - Business, Natural History and Personal Correspondence, 1888-02-1888-07 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    McCord, Mary
    Esperanza College
    Compagnie Universelle de Canal Interoceanique
  - Business and Natural History, 1888-08-1889 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Business and Natural History, 1890-06-1891-02 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Contains letters, financial statements, and telegrams
    Houston, J. B.
    Magee, Thomas
    San Francisco
  - Business and Natural History, 1891-03-1891-07 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Contains letters, financial statements, telegrams, invitations, and a memorandum
    Central America
  - Business and Natural History, 1891-08-1892-06 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    Contains letters, a schedule, a drawing, and a photograph copy
    Center Alexander
  - Business and Personal, 1892-07-1892-12 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Contains letters, receipts, and statements
    Dow, John M.
  - Personal, Undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Contains letters, fragments, and a resolution
    Allen, James
    San Salvador
  - Personal Family, 1856-06-1858-11 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    Contains letters and a poem
    Allen, Elizabeth K.
  - Personal Family, 1859-1860-06 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    Contains letters and a clipping
    Dow family
  - Personal Family Correspondence, 1860-11-1870-04 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Personal Family Correspondence, 1872-01-1872-03 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Personal Family Correspondence, 1872-04-1872-10 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Personal Family Correspondence, 1872-11-1876-07 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Business and Personal Family Correspondence, 1881-08-1885-04 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Business and Personal, 1885-06-1890-09 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    Contains letters, notes, and a compromise
  - Business and Personal Correspondence, 1891-1892 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    Contains letters and telegrams
  - Pacific Mail Steamship Company Business Records, 1857-1888 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    Contains certificates, statements, minutes, lists, records, tide table, and a newspaper
  - Pacific Mail Steamship Company, 1880-1885 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    Contains statements, records, tables, schedules, and a circular
    Monkey Hill
  - Pacific Mail Steamship Company Business, 1886-1889 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    Contains statements, reports, contracts, telegrams, analysis, and a testimony
  - Pacific Mail Steamship Company Business Records, 1889-1892 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    Contains reports, statements, schedules, tide tables, clippings, receipts, lists, payrolls, inventory, and a telegram
- Letterbook, 1857-1892
  - Letterbook, 1857-01-15-1859-01-12 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Joy, Joseph
    Mr. Skinner
    Sclater, P. L.
    Mozley, Brandon
    Mr. Bullay
    Hellen, Joseph
    Blanco y Eriqueros
    Sarg, Francisco
  - Letterbook, 1858-07-06-1865-04-24 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Letterbook, 1859-08-13-1864-09-24 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Letterbook, 1864-10-15-1873-02-19 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Letterbook, 1865-05-23-1873-07-15 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Letterbook, 1873-07-28-1879-03-15 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Letterbook, 1879-03-20-1881-03-26 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Letterbook, 1881-03-26-1883-07-28 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Letterbook, 1883-07-02-1885-01-28 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Letterbook, 1885-01-22-1888-04-05 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Letterbook, 1888-04-12-1892-07-23 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Logs, Diaries, and Nautical Guide, 1851-1892
  - Logs from S.S. "Columbus" and S.S. "Golden Age", 1851-09-29-1854-10-16 (Box 5)
    About trips from San Francisco to Acapulco, San Francisco to Panama, and Panama to San Francisco
    Acapulco
  - Logs from S.S. "Fremont" and S.S. "Columbus", 1852-02-02-1854-02-18 (Box 5)
    About trips from San Francisco to Panama
  - Log from an unnamed ship, 1859-06-08-1869-01-31 (Box 5)
    About trips between two unnamed locations
  - Log from S.S. "Costa Rica", 1870-04-11-1873-03-22 (Box 5)
  - Logs from S.S. "Honduras" and an unnamed ship, 1873-03-03-1875-04-26 (Box 5)
  - Logs from S.S. "Acapulco," S.S. "Colon," S.S. "City of Panama," and S.S. "City of Sydney", 1874-05-23-1876-06-12 (Box 5)
    About trips from New York to Aspinwall and back and New York to San Francisco and back
    New York
    Aspinwall
    Kingston
  - Log from S.S. "City of Sydney", 1876-06-21-1876-10-18 (Box 5)
    About trips from San Francisco to Sydney and New Zealand and back
    Sydney
    New Zealand
  - Private Journal from the S.S. "Columbus", 1856-11-17-1859-01-10 (Box 5)
  - Diary, 1877-03-28-1878-03-01 (Box 5)
  - Diary, 1880-02-12-1881-01-08 (Box 5)
  - Diary, 1884-01-09-1884-08-14 (Box 5)
  - Diary, 1887-01-24-1888-01-06 (Box 5)
  - Diary, 1888-01-01-1888-05-28 (Box 5)
  - Diary, 1890-01-01-1890-10-14 (Box 5)
  - Notebook and Diary, 1888-12-10-1891-06-19 (Box 5)
  - Diary, 1892-01-01-1892-07-22 (Box 5)
  - Reconnaissance hydrographique des cotes du Centre-Amerique, executee par la corvette La Brillante, sous le commandement de M. T. de Lapelin…, 1854 (Box 5)
    A two volume, handwritten, English translation
    Paris
- Personal Papers, 1851-1918
  - Dow-Allen Biographical and Genealogical Material, 1892, 1914; 1 (Box 6)
    Contains news clippings, genealogical sketch, and a letter
    Dow Family
    Allen Family
  - Dow Family Correspondence, 1851-1918; 2 (Box 6)
    Contains correspondence and poems
    Dow, Bertha
  - Personal Legal Papers, 1857-1877; 3 (Box 6)
    Contains legal documents and insurance policies
    New York City
  - Personal Legal Papers, 1885-1889; 4 (Box 6)
    Contains insurance policies, passports, and a contract
  - Personal Financial Papers, 1860-1869; 5 (Box 6)
    Contains account books, receipts, and invoices
  - Personal Financial Papers, 1870-1875; 6 (Box 6)
  - Personal Financial Papers, 1876-1892; 7 (Box 6)
    Contains checks, receipts, invoices, and certificates
  - Membership Papers, 1858-1888; 8 (Box 6)
    Contains certificates and circulars
- Photographs, 1860-1891
  - Daguerreotype of James Allen "John" Morrison, 1845; 15.3 x 12.2 cm (Box 7, Folder 1)
    Daguerreotypes
    half plate
  - Carte-de-visite album of caricatures, 1860; 15.4 x 12 cm (Box 7, Folder 2)
    Contains handwritten inscriptions below some cartes-de-visite.
    Caricatures
    Cartes-de-visite (card photographs)
    Albumen prints
  - Carte-de-visite album of caricatures, 1860; 15.5 x 14 cm (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - John Melmoth Dow, 1888-1891; Taber; W. Kurtz; 16.5 x 11 cm; 4 cards (Box 8, Folder 1)
    Dow, J. M. (John M.)
    Portraits
    Cabinet cards
  - Central America (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Home of Dr. M.S. Hine in San Jose, Costa Rica, 1866; 11.2 x 14.5 cm; 2 photographs; Mounted on card (Box 8, Folder 2)
      Costa Rica
      Houses
    - Guatemala, 1874; Berbruner, Emilio Sr.; 16.7 x 11 cm; 7 cabinet cards (Box 8, Folder 2)
      Laborers, gardens, coffee
    - Central America, 1874; Imery, N.Y.B.; 16.7 x 11 cm; 7 cabinet cards (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Nicaragua, 1870; 15 x 12.8 cm; 3 photographs; Mounted on card (Box 8, Folder 4)
    Nicaragua
  - Panoramic view of Sydney and Port Jackson, 1876; Turner and Henderson; 107 x 23 cm; Folded panorama mounted inside cover. (Box 8, Folder 5)
    Sydney, Australia
    Port Jackson, Australia
    Panoramas
  - Ruinas de San Salvador, 1865; Moncreiff Foto; 26 x 20 cm and smaller; 15 photographs; Mounted on card. Typewritten captions mounted on card below photograph. (Box 8, Folder 6)
    San Salvador, El Salvador
  - Panama, 1886; 25.3 x 20.1 cm; 10 photographs; Mounted on card. Handwritten inscriptions on verso. (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Guatemala, 1858-1859; Fitzgibbon, John H., 1816?-1882; Fitzgibbon, Wm. (William); 20.2 x 23.7 cm; 20 photographs; Mounted on card. Include handwritten inscriptions. (Box 8, Folder 8-11)
    Salted paper prints
  - Front Street, Colon/Aspinwall, 1870; 18.7 x 23.7 cm; 2 photographs (Box 8, Folder 12)
    Colon, Panama
  - Central America, 1870; 13 x 27.2 cm and smaller; 7 photographs; Mounted on card. Include handwritten inscriptions. (Box 8, Folder 13)
    Includes one photographic print of a drawing of the P.M. SS City of Sydney.
    Acapolco, Mexico
  - Panama, 1870; 28 x 35 cm and smaller; 3 photographs; Mounted on card. Include handwritten inscriptions. (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Panama, 1870; Herbruger, E. Jr.; 29.3 x 34.3 cm; 2 photographs; Mounted on card. Include handwritten inscriptions and studio stamp. (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Guatemala, 1874; 25.8 x 38.8 cm; 5 photographs; Mounted on card. Include handwritten inscriptions. (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - John Melmoth Dow portraits, 2 photographs (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Portrait of John Melmoth Dow, 1872; Kurtz, W.; 25.5 x 20.2 cm; Mounted on board, printed with studio information. (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Portrait of John Melmoth Dow, 1880; 40.6 x 31.2 cm; Mounted on oval board. (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Carte-de-visite album, 1860-1870; 30.5 x 23.8 cm; Leather bound album with cameos on clasps. (Box 14)
    Includes photographs of members of the Dow family. Contains handwritten inscriptions below some cartes-de-visite.
    Photograph albums
- Miscellany and Memorabilia, 1851-1896
  - "Telegraphic Code: Pacific Mail Steamship Company", 1885-01-15 (Box 9)
  - "Freight and Shipping Rates", 1878 (Box 9)
  - Scrapbook, 1855-1896 (Box 9)
  - "Notebook", 1857-1859 (Box 9)
  - Memo book, re Orchids, Undated (Box 9)
  - "Notebook, Expenses - 1888, Trip to Europe", 1888 (Box 9)
    Europe
  - "Poems, 1851-1856", 1851-1856 (Box 9)
  - Journal, 1876-12-02-1878 (Box 9)
  - "Memoranda, 1860-1861", 1860-1861 (Box 9)
  - "1861 Measurements and Distances", 1861 (Box 9)
  - "Notebook 1860-1865", 1860-1865 (Box 9)
  - "El Constitutional", 1865 (Box 9)
    Contains a broadside attached to a hand-painted flags
    Canas, Juan J.
  - Sketchbook, Undated (Box 10)
  - "Ocean Mosses", 1855-12-10 (Box 10)
    Contains bound, pressed mosses
    Allen, Lizzie K.
  - Pressed flower, Undated (Box 10)
    Contains a single dried, pressed Cattleya Dowiana
  - Mounted picture, 1865 (Box 10)
    Contains a picture and description of Cattleya Dowiana
  - Passenger lists from S.S. Rhaetia, 1888 (Box 10)
  - Memo book, Undated (Box 10)
    Contains notes on various subjects with some daily entries
  - Menus, a program, trade cards, tickets, and an invitation, Undated (Box 10)
- Publications, 1854-1891
  - Bulletin of the Proceedings of the American Ethnological Society in the City of New York, 1861-1862 (Box 11)
  - Arrangement of Families of Birds, 1866 (Box 11)
    Contains eight pages
  - Sculptured Anthropoid Ape Hands, Found in or Near the Valley of the John Day River, A Tributary of the Columbia River, Oregon, by James Terry, 1891; Terry, James (Box 11)
  - A Week at Port-Royal, 1855; Hill, Richard (Box 11)
    Montego-Bay
  - The Publications of the American Tract Society, Undated (Box 11)
    Contains incomplete Volume 1 of Series II
  - A Builder's Trip Across the Continent, 1886; Tucker, John J. (Box 11)
  - Union League Club of New York, Annual Reports of Executive Committee and Treasurer, By-Laws and House Rules, 1870-1871 (Box 11)
  - Speculations, Solar Heat, Gravitation, and Sun Spots, 1891; Kedzie, J. H. (Box 11)
    Chicago
  - The American Museum of Natural History, New York City. Annual Report of the Trustees, Act of Incorporation, Constitution, By-Laws and List of Members. For the Year, 1890-1891 (Box 11)
  - Science, 1885-10 (Box 11)
    Vol. VI No. 142
  - Fishes of Central America, XIV. An Account of the Fishes of States of Central America, based on Collections made by Capt. J. M. Dow, F. Godman, Esq. and O. Salvin, Esq. By Albert Gunther Read March 22, 1864 and Dec. 13, 1866. Pages 377-494 with Plates LXIII to LXXXVII, 1864 (Box 11)
    Dow, James M.
    Godman, F.
    Salvin, O.
    Gunther, Albert
  - Extract from "Curtis's Botanical Magazine" Cattleya Dowiana, 1865-1866 (Box 11)
  - Journal of the Marine Biological Association of the United Kingdom, 1888 (Box 11)
    London
  - "The Humming Bird" - A Monthly Scientific, Artistic, and Industrial Review, 1891 (Box 11)
    Vol. 1, No. 1
    Boucard, Adolphe
  - Catalogue - Leonard Brothers & Co., Undated (Box 11)
    Sale Listing of Furniture, etc.
  - Extracts from Proceedings of the Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia, 1859, 1863, 1864, 1886 (Box 12)
  - Extracts from The American Journal of Science and Arts, 1866-1873 (Box 12)
  - Extracts from Boston Society of Natural History, 1857, 1866 (Box 12)
  - Extracts from the Annals of the New York Academy of Sciences, 1861, 1887, 1905 (Box 12)